Guide to the Norman Douglas Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- 1968-1993 Acquisitions, 1864-1967; Series I; 16.31; (42 boxes)
  - Correspondence, 1874-1960; Series II
    - Norman Douglas Incoming Correspondence
      - Gulbransson, Olaf, 1908, undated (Box 17, Folder 253)
      - "H" general, 1914-1944 (Box 17, Folder 254)
        Maurice Hewlett
      - H.D., 1939 October 10 (Box 17, Folder 255)
      - Helston, John, 1913, undated (Box 17, Folder 256)
      - Hunt, Violet, 1930, undated (Box 17, Folder 257)
      - Hutchinson, F. W., 1938 (Box 17, Folder 258)
      - Hutton, Edward, 1921-1938 (Box 17, Folder 259)
      - Huxley, Aldous, 1922-1937 (Box 17, Folder 260)
      - "I" general, 1920-1933, undated (Box 17, Folder 261)
      - "J" general, 1914-1939 (Box 17, Folder 262)
        Thomas Spencer Jerome
        Augustus John (3)
        James Joyce
      - "K" general, 1912-1938 (Box 18, Folder 263)
      - King, Alec, 1946, 1949 (Box 18, Folder 264)
      - "L" general, 1914-1940, undated (Box 18, Folder 265-66)
        Ada Leverson
      - Lawrence, D. H., 1920-1927 (Box 18, Folder 267)
      - Lawrence, Frieda, undated (Box 18, Folder 268)
      - Levy, Oscar, 1913-[1940?] (Box 18, Folder 269)
      - "M" general, 1913-1940 (Box 18, Folder 270-71)
        Compton MacKenzie
        John Masefield
        George Moore
        Harold Monro
        J. Middleton Murry
      - Magnus, Maurice, 1917-1920 (Box 18, Folder 272-74)
        See also: American Consular Service, "A" general, Box 17, folder 225
      - Mann, F. W., 1920-1921 (Box 18, Folder 275)
      - Mari, René, 1933-1934 (Box 18, Folder 276)
        See also: Box 17, folder 250
      - Masciandaro, Ettore, 1948 (Box 18, Folder 277)
      - Maudsley, Henry, 1899-1907 (Box 18, Folder 278)
      - Mavrogordato, John, 1918-1932 (Box 18, Folder 279-85)
      - "N" general, 1914-1938 (Box 18, Folder 286)
      - "O" general, 1914-1925, undated (Box 18, Folder 287)
      - Orioli, Giuseppe, 1937-1939, undated (Box 18, Folder 288)
      - Ouida, 1901-1903, undated (Box 18, Folder 289-96)
      - "P" general, 1910-1949, undated (Box 18, Folder 297)
      - Papa, Emilio, 1937-1948, undated (Box 19, Folder 298-308)
        See also: Box 27, folders 427-29; Box 30, folder 516
      - Phillpotts, Eden, 1913-1918 (Box 19, Folder 309)
      - "R" general, 1913-1940 (Box 19, Folder 310)
        Arthur Rubenstein
        Bruce Richmond
      - Robertson, Cecile Wallin, 1922-1948 (Box 19, Folder 311)
      - "S" general, 1913-1952 (Box 19, Folder 312-13)
        Rafael Sabatini
        Carl Salsa
        Charles Scott-Moncrieff (4)
        May Sinclair (2)
        Edward Storer (2)
        G. S. Street
      - Saintsbury, George, 1921-1926 (Box 19, Folder 314)
      - Strachey, Lytton, 1923-1928 (Box 19, Folder 315)
      - "T" general, 1909-1930 (Box 19, Folder 316)
      - Tarkington, Booth, 1913-1925 (Box 19, Folder 317)
      - Tarkington, Louisa C., 1913-1921 (Box 19, Folder 318)
      - Thomas, Edward, 1911-1913 (Box 19, Folder 319)
      - Tomlinson, H. M., 1913-1930 (Box 19, Folder 320)
      - "V" general, 1918-1951 (Box 19, Folder 321)
        Including Carl Van Vechten
      - "W" general, 1894-1949 (Box 19, Folder 322)
        Catherine Wells
        Rebecca West (2)
        Leonard Woolf
      - Walpole, Hugh, 1913, undated (Box 20, Folder 323)
      - Wolfe, Teddy, 1924-1925, undated (Box 20, Folder 324)
        See also: Oversize, Box 42, folder 647
      - Wolton, Eric, 1921, undated (Box 20, Folder 325)
        See also: Box 21, folders 335-39
      - Woolf, Cecil, 1950-1951 (Box 20, Folder 326)
      - "Y" general, 1919-1921 (Box 20, Folder 327)
      - Miscellaneous, 1881-1949, undated (Box 20, Folder 328-30)
    - Norman Douglas Outgoing Correspondence
      - "A" general, 1951 (Box 21, Folder 331)
      - Aldington, Richard, undated (Box 21, Folder 332)
      - Beevers, John L., 1931-1934 (Box 21, Folder 333)
      - The Bookseller, 1943 (Box 21, Folder 334)
      - Bryher, 1924-1949 (Box 21, Folder 335-39)
      - Byrne, Mr., 1951 (Box 21, Folder 340)
      - Collamore, H. Bacon, 1925 (Box 21, Folder 341)
      - Conrad, Joseph, 1925 October 23 (Box 21, Folder 342)
        Letter to Conrad's literary executor, name unknown.
      - Douglas, Archibald
        - Calendar of letters, undated (Box 21, Folder 343)
        - Letters, 1916-1924 (Box 21, Folder 344-50)
        - Letters, 1925-1930 (Box 22, Folder 351-57)
        - Letters, 1931-1936 (Box 23, Folder 358-65)
        - Letters, 1937-1942 (Box 24, Folder 366-74)
        - Letters, 1943-1949 (Box 25, Folder 375-84)
        - Letters, 1950-1952 (Box 26, Folder 385-87)
      - Duncan, Ethel de C., 1918-1934 (Box 26, Folder 388)
      - "G" general, 1915, 1924, undated (Box 26, Folder 389)
      - Grant Richards, Ltd., 1921 (Box 26, Folder 390)
      - "H" general, 1925, 1943 (Box 26, Folder 391)
      - H.D., 1922-1951, undated (Box 26, Folder 392)
        Includes a note by Bryher to Kenneth Macpherson explaining why she is giving him the letters
      - Holliday, Terence, 1925-1930 (Box 26, Folder 393)
      - Hutchinson, F. W., 1939-1951 (Box 26, Folder 394-402)
      - Hutchinson, Kay, 1928-1939, undated (Box 26, Folder 403)
      - Jeffreys, David G., 1945-1951 (Box 26, Folder 404-15)
      - Jehly, Vanda Douglass, 1877-1889 (Box 26, Folder 416)
      - Johnson, Arthur Johnson, John Johnson, Viola, 1945-1951 (Box 26, Folder 417)
      - King, Willie (William), 1944-1947 (Box 26, Folder 418-20)
      - King, Willie (William), 1948-1949, undated (Box 27, Folder 421-22)
      - "L" general, 1936, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 423)
      - Lowenfels, Walter, 1926 (Box 27, Folder 424)
      - "M" general, 1909-1917 (Box 27, Folder 425)
      - Macpherson, Kenneth, 1930-1951 (Box 27, Folder 426-38)
        Includes enclosed letters from Emilio Papa.
      - Magnus, Maurice, 1920, undated (Box 27, Folder 439)
      - Masciandaro, Ettore, 1948 (Box 27, Folder 440)
      - Mason, Harold T., 1925-1928 (Box 27, Folder 441)
      - Mavrogordato, John, 1921-1926 (Box 27, Folder 442-56)
      - Mavrogordato, John, 1927-1933 (Box 28, Folder 457-74)
      - Mavrogordato, John, 1934-1947, undated (Box 29, Folder 475-86)
      - Parsons, Ian, 1936-1938 (Box 29, Folder 487)
      - Pinker, James B., 1932 (Box 29, Folder 488)
      - "S" general, 1920-1950 (Box 29, Folder 489)
      - Singer, Godfrey F., 1927-1933 (Box 29, Folder 490)
      - "T" general, 1937 (Box 29, Folder 491)
      - Tomlinson, H. M., 1915-1944, undated (Box 29, Folder 492)
      - "V" general, 1936 (Box 29, Folder 493)
      - Unidentified, 1925 (Box 29, Folder 494)
    - Third Party Correspondence
      - Douglas, Robin
        - Letters to Time, 1958 January 13 (Box 30, Folder 495)
          See also: Box 30, folders 509-11
      - Hutchinson, F. W.
        - Banting, John, 1939 (Box 30, Folder 496)
        - Cunard, Nancy, 1938-1955 (Box 30, Folder 497-500)
        - Cunard, Nancy: clippings regarding atomic energy, 1954-1955 (Box 30, Folder 501)
        - Douglas, Marion, 1948 (Box 30, Folder 502)
        - Douglas, Robin, 1941 (Box 30, Folder 503)
        - Gordon-Crotch, Martha, 1940-1941 (Box 30, Folder 504)
        - Levy, Oscar, 1939-1945 (Box 30, Folder 505-06)
        - Miscellaneous, 1946, undated (Box 30, Folder 507)
      - Lawrence, D. H., 1920 (Box 30, Folder 508)
        Transcripts of 3 letters by Lawrence, J. E. Brooks and poem, "Green," by Lawrence attached to letter.
      - Macpherson, Kenneth
        - Letters written as Douglas's literary executor, 1954-1960 (Box 30, Folder 509-11)
        - Letters written as Douglas's literary executor: related clippings (Box 42, Folder 658)
        - Greene, Graham, 1954 (Box 30, Folder 512)
          Includes typescript, corrected, of Greene's review of Pinorman: A Composite Portrait by Richard Aldington.
          See also: Box 17, folder 248
        - National Portrait Gallery, 1960 (Box 30, Folder 513)
        - Woolf, Cecil, 1954, 1960 (Box 30, Folder 514)
        - Miscellaneous, 1954-1960 (Box 30, Folder 515-16)
          Includes letters from Harold Acton, Bryher, Edwin Cerio, Alan Clodd, Nancy Cunard, Archie Douglas, Robin Douglas, and Roger Senhouse.
      - Magnus, Maurice, 1915-1920 (Box 30, Folder 517-18)
        Includes letters from Michel Russotti and letter from Magnus to "Mr. Golding."
      - Orioli, Giuseppe
        - Macpherson, Kenneth, 1931-1933, undated (Box 30, Folder 519)
        - Mathers, E. Powys, 1931 March 30 (Box 30, Folder 520)
      - Miscellaneous, 1911-1947 (Box 30, Folder 521)
        Includes letter from John Mavrogordato to "King"
  - Subject Files, 1871-1967; Series III
    Series III is arranged alphabetically by the name of the individual concerned.
    Series III consists of documents related to the work of other authors collected by Douglas and Kenneth Macpherson. This material has been arranged alphabetically by name and consists of written works, including typescripts of Maurice Magnus's and Giuseppe Orioli's books.
    - Aldington, Richard, "Liberty under Bureaucracy:" printed version, 1931 May 5 (Box 31, Folder 522)
    - Brown, W., "Fengh and Dee:" manuscript, 1872 June 22 (Box 31, Folder 523)
    - Cunard, Nancy: poems, 1944, undated (Box 31, Folder 524)
    - Gulbransson, Olaf: notebooks, 1871-1900, undated (Box 31, Folder 525-27)
    - H.D., "Christe Eleison Ageina:" typescript, [circa. 1933] (Box 31, Folder 528)
    - Hutchinson, F. W.: checks to Douglas, 1941-1942 (Box 31, Folder 529)
    - Macpherson, Kenneth
      - Lists of manuscripts sold by Douglas to Macpherson, undated (Box 31, Folder 529a)
      - Material regarding Capri fire, 1967 (Box 31, Folder 530)
      - Omnes Eodem Cogimur: Printer's proofs, [circa 1952] (Box 31, Folder 531)
      - Omnes Eodem Cogimur: Miscellaneous, 1933-1955 (Box 31, Folder 532)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 31, Folder 533)
    - Magnus, Maurice
      - Legal papers, 1914-1920 (Box 31, Folder 534)
      - "Memoirs of the Foreign Legion:" clippings, 1924-1926 (Box 31, Folder 535)
      - "Memoirs of Golden Russia:" typescript, undated (Box 31, Folder 536)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 31, Folder 537)
    - Orioli, Giuseppe
      Adventures of a Bookseller
      - "To India with Norman: Editor's Note:" typescript, undated (Box 31, Folder 538)
      - Typescripts, undated (Box 31, Folder 539)
      - Typescripts, undated (Box 32, Folder 540)
      - Sotheby's sale of Orioli's Douglas manuscripts, 1937 (Box 32, Folder 540a)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 32, Folder 541)
    - Rolfe, Frederick (Baron Corvo), "Hubert's Arthur:" manuscript draft, undated (Box 32, Folder 542)
    - Turner, Reginald: will, undated (Box 32, Folder 543)
    - Wilson, R. N. D., "Vietri-Sul-Marc:" typescript, undated (Box 32, Folder 544)
    - Wolfe, Edward: painting, undated (Box 32, Folder 545)
    - Unknown, "An Englishman Looks at Italy": typescript, undated (Box 32, Folder 546)
  - Personal Papers, 1864-1964; Series IV
    Series IV is organized into two subseries: Norman Douglas (further arranged alphabetically by subject), and Douglas Family (further arranged by family name).
    Series IV focuses on Douglas's private life, though there is also material that probably relates to The English Review. Material on Douglas's funeral includes Douglas's instructions on the distribution of his property. A series of pocket diaries, which cover most of his life, act as a record of Douglas's correspondence. He noted daily to whom he was writing and often where he was traveling. The collection also contains six ornithological diaries dating from 1885 to 1898. They record Douglas's bird watching in Germany and Austria.
    The series also includes photograph albums and sets of photographs, most taken and annotated by Douglas and Pino Orioli on trips in Calabria and other Italian locations. Subjects of photographs include the 1952 funeral and gravesite of Norman Douglas.
    In the Douglas Family section, Elsa FitzGibbon's diary of 1901-1902 provides a rare view of Douglas's married life.
    - Norman Douglas
      - Address book, undated (Box 33, Folder 547)
      - Artwork (Box 42, Folder 659)
      - Death instructions, 1949-1951 (Box 33, Folder 548)
      - [ The English Review papers], undated (Box 33, Folder 549)
      - Financial papers, 1948-1952 (Box 33, Folder 550)
      - Funeral oration, 1952 February 10 (Box 33, Folder 551)
      - Funeral papers, 1952 (Box 33, Folder 552)
        See also: Oversize, Box 41, folder 650
      - Honorary citizenship of Capri, 1946 (Box 33, Folder 553)
      - List of available copies of his works, undated (Box 33, Folder 553a)
      - List of Capri literature, undated (Box 33, Folder 554)
      - Notes on a marmot's skull, undated (Box 33, Folder 555)
      - Ornithological diaries, 1885-1898 (Box 33, Folder 556-61)
      - Photographs
        - Calabria, undated (Box 34, Folder 562-63)
        - Douglas and friends, undated (Box 34, Folder 564)
        - Funeral and grave, 1953 (Box 34, Folder 565)
        - General, 1892, 1898, undated (Box 34, Folder 566-67)
          See also: Oversize, Box 41, folder 651
        - Sent to Macpherson, undated (Box 34, Folder 568)
        - Trip to Calabria with Emilio, 1936 (Box 34, Folder 569)
      - Pocket diaries, 1890, 1907-1909 (Box 34, Folder 570-72)
      - Pocket diaries, 1910-1926 (Box 35, Folder 573-81)
      - Pocket diaries, 1927-1946 (Box 36, Folder 582-91)
      - Pocket diaries, 1947-1951 (Box 37, Folder 592-94)
      - School papers, 1875-1893 (Box 37, Folder 595)
      - Shopping and laundry lists, undated (Box 37, Folder 596)
      - Smuggling book, circa 1930s (Box 37, Folder 597)
      - Miscellaneous, 1952 (Box 37, Folder 598-99)
        See also: Oversize, Box 42, folder 652
    - Douglas Family
      - John Sholto Douglass and Vanda Douglass Jehly
        - Correspondence, 1874-1908 (Box 38, Folder 600-01)
        - Legal papers, 1864-1874 (Box 38, Folder 602)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 42, Folder 653)
      - Elsa FitzGibbon Douglas
        - Diary, 1901-1902 (Box 38, Folder 603)
      - Other Family
        - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 38, Folder 604-05)
  - Material Related to Norman Douglas, 1926-1961; Series V
    Series V is organized into two subseries: Individual Works and Subjects. The first subseries is arranged alphabetically by author, and the second alphabetically by subject title.
    Series V contains a variety of sources about Norman Douglas, his life, and his work. The articles and other material were probably collected by Douglas and Kenneth Macpherson. The documents cover the following topics: Capri, Collecting Norman Douglas, Norman Douglas (biographical and literary analysis), and Norman Douglas and his Circle (when Douglas himself is not the focus of the article). To facilitate use, longer articles have been listed separately under Individual Works, while the rest have been grouped under Subjects. The second section also includes reviews of several Douglas biographies. Reviews were often followed by "Letters to the editor."
    Also included is Provenance Material relating to Kenneth Macpherson's research on the value of the Douglas papers, including bibliographies, extracts from bookdealers' catalogs, and clippings.
    - Individual Works
      - Acattolical, Cimitero, "Commiato da Norman Douglas", 1952 February 10 (Box 39, Folder 606)
      - Aldington, Richard, "Errant Knight of of Capri" (2 copies and Douglas's response), 1941-1942 (Box 39, Folder 607)
      - Bryher
        - The Heart to Artemis, chap. 16: typescript, undated (Box 39, Folder 608)
        - Interview of Douglas: notes, undated (Box 39, Folder 609)
      - Canino, Elena, "Lucina Caprese" (p. 8-13), 1953 (Box 39, Folder 610)
      - Cunard, Nancy, Grand Man: typescript draft, 1953 (Box 39, Folder 611)
      - Davenport, John and Cleverdon, Douglas, "Norman Douglas: A Biographical Portrait" (radio broadcast), 1957 (Box 39, Folder 612)
      - Holloway, Mark, Norman Douglas: A Biography: typescript (photocopy), [1972] (Box 39, Folder 613-16)
      - Holloway, Mark, Norman Douglas: A Biography: typescript (photocopy), [1972] (Box 40, Folder 617-18)
      - Lambert, Jean, "Esquisses pour un portrait de Norman Douglas", 1956 April 7 (Box 40, Folder 619)
      - Moravia, Alberto
        - [Column on Norman Douglas], 1951 September 23 (Box 40, Folder 620)
        - "Un Libro Preistorico", 1946 August 8 (Box 40, Folder 621)
      - Norman, Sylvia, "Douglas On Capri", 1952 August (Box 40, Folder 622)
      - "Norman Douglas: A Tribute" (radio broadcast)
        - Script, 1948 (Box 40, Folder 623)
        - Correspondence, 1948-1949 (Box 40, Folder 624)
      - "Portrait of Norman Douglas" (and responses by K. Macpherson and J. I. Davis), 1952 (Box 40, Folder 625)
      - Praz, Mario, "Norman Douglas", 1933 April 23 (Box 40, Folder 626)
      - Sidney University Literary Society (extract of minutes), 1934 July 5 (Box 40, Folder 627)
      - Senhouse, Roger, "Norman Douglas an Appreciation on his 80th Birthday" (typescript and printed versions), 1949 (Box 40, Folder 628)
      - Szladits, Lola L., "Norman Douglas, Gymnasiast", 1959 June (Box 40, Folder 629)
      - Webster, H. T., "Norman Douglas: A Reconstruction", 1950 April (Box 40, Folder 630)
    - Subjects
      - Capri, 1946-1950 (Box 40, Folder 631)
      - Collecting Norman Douglas, 1929-1958 (Box 40, Folder 632)
      - Norman Douglas, 1917-1968, undated (Box 40, Folder 633)
      - Norman Douglas and his Circle, 1925-1954 (Box 40, Folder 634)
      - Reviews of
        - Aldington, Richard, Pinorman, 1954 (Box 40, Folder 635)
        - Cunard, Nancy, Grand Man, Memories of Norman Douglas (with response by Nancy Cunard), 1954 (Box 40, Folder 636)
        - Cunard, Nancy, Grand Man, Memories of Norman Douglas, 1954 (Box 40, Folder 637)
        - Dawkins, R. M., Norman Douglas, undated (Box 40, Folder 638)
        - FitzGibbon, Constantine, Norman Douglas. A Pictorial Record, 1953 (Box 40, Folder 639)
        - MacDonald, Edward D., A Bibliography of the Writings of Norman Douglas, 1927 May (Box 40, Folder 640)
        - MacGillivray, Richard, Norman Douglas, 1933 (Box 40, Folder 641)
        - Norman Douglas: A Selection of His Works, 1955 September 22 (Box 40, Folder 642)
        - Tomlinson, H. M., Norman Douglas, 1931-1953 (Box 40, Folder 643)
        - Miscellaneous, 1926-1961 (Box 40, Folder 644-45)
    - Provenance Material
      These papers are related to Kenneth Macpherson's efforts to document the value of the Douglas papers.
      - Bibliographies, undated (Box 41, Folder 645a)
      - Bibliographies, undated (Box 41, Folder 645b)
      - Correspondence and clippings lists, [1967?] (Box 41, Folder 645c)
      - Dealer catalog extracts, 1926-1957, undated (Box 41, Folder 645d)
      - Invoice, 1957 (Box 41, Folder 645e)
      - Register of the University of California's Norman Douglas collection, 1956 (Box 41, Folder 645f)
  - Oversize
    Oversize material contains oversize material from Series I, II, and IV in a parallel arrangement.
    - Writings
      - Books and Pamphlets
        - London Street Games: research material, [circa 1915] (Box 42, Folder 646)
    - Correspondence
      - Norman Douglas Correspondence
        - Wolfe, Teddy, undated (Box 42, Folder 647)
      - Third Party Correspondence
        - Macpherson, Kenneth, letters written as Douglas's literary executor: related clippings, 1959 (Box 42, Folder 648)
    - Personal Papers
      - Norman Douglas
        - Artwork, undated (Box 42, Folder 649)
        - Funeral papers, 1952 (Box 42, Folder 650)
        - Photographs: general, 1898, undated (Box 42, Folder 651)
        - Miscellaneous, 1952 (Box 42, Folder 652)
      - Douglas Family
        - John Sholto Douglass and Vanda Douglass Jehly, miscellaneous, undated (Box 42, Folder 653)
- 1993-2003 Acquisitions, circa 1930-1952; Series II; 0.21; (1 box)
  The 1993-2003 Acquisitions are organized into three series: I. Letters. II. Writings. III. Additions 1995-2003.
  The 1993-2003 Acquisitions encompass accessions of single manuscripts and small groups of manuscripts and other papers, by or pertaining to Norman Douglas, acquired by the library from a variety of sources.
  General
  Formerly classed as GEN MSS 142.
  - Letters, Series I
    Arranged alphabetically by recipient.
    Letters consist of outgoing letters by Norman Douglas, 1931-1949.
    - Letter: Capri, to Archie Douglas, 1948 October 29; 1 item (1 leaf); 18 cm. (Box 43, Folder 1)
      Autograph letter (possibly incomplete) concerning Douglas's health and financial situation.
      Purchased in 1993.
    - Letters to Marion Whitworth Douglas, 1941-1949; 14 items. (Box 43, Folder 2-6)
      12 autograph letters signed, some enclosing photographic postcards of Capri, and 2 autograph postcards signed, most dating from 1947. The letters discuss Archie's work in Africa and Marion's plans to join him there, Douglas's health and financial situation, possible names for the child Marion is expecting, and Douglas's impressions of America and Americans. The letter of 1941 January 19 congratulates Marion on the birth of Victoria Douglas. With: 13 envelopes.
      Autograph letter signed of 1947 January 18 includes a photograph of Norman Douglas, inscribed to Marion "from Uncle Norman, 18 Jan 1947."
    - Letter: Florence, to Walter Lowenfels, 1931 April 22; 1 item (1 leaf); 14cm. (Box 43, Folder 7)
      Autograph postcard signed.
    - Letter: 7 Unghia Marina, Isola Capri, to Albert P. Sachs, 1947 January 26; 1 item (1 leaf); 19 cm. (Box 43, Folder 8)
      Autograph letter signed thanking Sachs for a check and discussing Douglas's financial situation. With envelope.
      With: photograph of Norman Douglas, inscribed by him to Albert Sachs, Capri, Jan. 1947.
  - Writings, [1925 Apr]; Series II
    - "A Little Discovery," typescript corrected, signed, [1925 April]; 1 item (8 leaves); 26 cm. (Box 43, Folder 9)
      With: manuscript of music in Norman Douglas's hand, inscribed " 'Fischerlied' by Richard Wagner. Taken down: Posilipo, August 1898." (Song referenced in typescript.) 1 item (1 leaf); 33 cm.
      With: ALS to Miss Hahner, 1925 Apr 16. 1 item (1 leaf); 29 cm.
  - Additions 1995-2003, Series III
    Arranged chronologically by acquisition date.
    - Cunard, Nancy
      - Letters to David Low, 1954-1956; 4 items. (Box 43, Folder 10)
        The letters discuss Low's review of Great Man, Cunard's translation of Fountains in the Sand, and Richard Aldington.
        Purchased in 1996.
    - Douglas, Norman
      - Letter: Monaco, to David Low, 1938 December 9; 1 item (1 l.); 27 cm. (Box 43, Folder 11)
        Autograph letter signed to Low discussing his move to Monaco, his finances, mutual friends and a biography of Ouida.
      - Letter: Florence, to W[alter] L[owenfels], 1929 May 7; 1 item (1 leaf); 25 cm. (Box 43, Folder 12)
        Autograph letter signed to Lowenfels discussing personal news and travel plans.
        Purchased in 1997.
      - Letter: to "Wilder", [1927] April 30; 1 item (1 leaf); 18 cm. (Box 43, Folder 13)
        Autograph letter signed making a dinner engagement.
    - Low, David
      - "Arcades Ambo," holograph, undated; 1 item (10 l.); 29 cm. (Box 43, Folder 14)
        Account of the first meeting of Charles Prentice and David Low with Norman Douglas and Pino Orioli in Florence in 1930.
      - "Norman Douglas. Varia," holograph notebooks, 1967; 2 items. (Box 43, Folder 15)
        2 notebooks containing entries concerning the life of Norman Douglas.
    - MacPherson, Kenneth
      - "Last Crop. Some Uncollected Studies by Norman Douglas, edited by Kenneth Macpherson," typescript, corrected, 1957 September; 1 item (132 p.); 28 cm. (Box 43, Folder 16-18)
    - Oriolo, Giuseppe